我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我妈离开我们的时候  她怀有身孕
When my mother left us, she was pregnant.
爸爸  我很抱歉没早点告诉你
Dad, I'm so sorry that I didn't tell you sooner.
你好  我是沃利  弗朗辛的儿子
Hi, I'm Wally. I'm Francine's son.
你要巴里变得更快
You want Barry to get faster?
他有越多能量  我就能取走越多
The more power he has, the more I can take.
不要让他把我关回去
Don't let him take me back there.
我不会
I won't.
你会帮我的
You're going to help me
以换回你女儿的性命
in return for your daughter's life.
我会帮你偷闪电侠的速度
I will help you steal the Flash's speed.
我知道自己速度相当快
I know I'm moving pretty fast,
但我保证你没听过这个
but stop me if you've heard this one before.
男孩邂逅女孩  每天都会发生的事
Boy meets girl. Happens every day.
只不过这位男孩曾被闪电击中过
Except this boy was struck by lightning
然后变成了世上速度最快的人
and became the fastest man alive.
所以万事绝不简单
So nothing is ever that simple.
我天
Oh, my--
小心
Careful!
老天  抱歉
Oh, boy. Sorry!
没事
It's all good.
反正这些花不是给我的  对吧
Those weren't for me anyway, right?
是给你的
They were.
我只是没想到玫瑰这么易燃
I didn't realize roses were so flammable.
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
重要的是心意
Well, it's the-- it's the thought that counts.
还有就是  做好消防安全管理
And, you know, and proper fire safety management,
-那是最重要的  -死的
- that--that counts most. - Yes.
我之前总觉得自己运气背
I have spent most of my life feeling very unlucky.
是吗  那现在呢
Yeah, and now?
感觉像是再次被闪电击中
Feels like I've been struck by lightning twice.
救命
Help!
救我
Help me...
闪电侠  你所拥有的一切
Flash, everything you have
都将是我的
will be mine.
-不  -不
- No! - No!
不
No!
中城警局
好了  我的办公桌在那里
Okay, so there's my desk.
楼上是反犯罪小组和犯罪现场鉴证实验室
Upstairs is anti-crime and the CSI lab--
巴里就在那里工作
that's where Barry works.
这是我们的非机密档案
And we have the open files...
而那是只铅笔
And that is a pencil.
那是订书机
That stapler.
好吧  抱歉  沃利
Okay. Sorry, Wally.
显然你姐姐遗传到了搞笑基因
Obviously, your sister got the funny genes.
队长  来认识一下
Captain. I want you to meet somebody.
这是我儿子沃利·韦斯特
This is my son Wally West.
帅小伙儿啊  乔
Handsome young man, Joe.
他是韦斯特家人  想不帅都难
Hey, he's a West. He can't help that.
你老爹可是位超牛的警探
Your pops here is a hell of a detective.
显然并不是
Obviously not.
很高兴认识你  沃利
Well, pleasure to meet you, Wally.
不管怎样  很高兴你来了  沃利
Anyway, I'm glad you're here, Wally.
是啊  我一直想有个弟弟呢
Yeah, I've always wanted a baby brother.
那个白人跟屁虫怎样
What about the white shadow?
你开玩笑吧  不过...
You're joking, but...
也对  我们的确那么叫巴里
yeah, we did call Barry that.
他一直很忙
Well, he's been pretty busy.
他有一大堆要四处奔忙的事
He's doing a whole lot of running around.
但我们可以吃顿晚餐  一家人
But why don't we do dinner? The whole family.
我另有安排了
I, uh, I got plans.
爱瑞丝下厨
Oh, Iris'll cook.
爸  我们才刚见面
Dad, we just met the kid.
可不想把他毒死了
We don't want to kill him.
好  那我们出去吃  中餐
All right, we do takeout. Chinese.
什么都可以  来吧
Whatever. Come on.
你咋没戴手铐  跟踪狂
Where are your cuffs, taillights?
快点  走
Come on, let's go.
你认识那家伙
You know that kid?
不  不认识
Uh, no--no.
你知道  大家都说
You know, it's just what they say.
我长着张大众脸
I got one of those faces.
那我们晚饭见
I'll see you guys at dinner.
好的
Uh, okay.
我可以和你聊会儿吗
Any chance I could chat with you for a minute?
可以  怎么了  警探
Yeah, what's up, detective?
我在和爱瑞丝说话
Oh, uh, I-I meant Iris.
是啊  这里不需要你了
Yeah, you're not needed.
总有地方需要我
I am needed-- somewhere.
我去了
I'm...go there.
有什么能帮你的吗
What can I do for you?
我只是想和你聊聊
I just wanted to talk with you, um,
巴里的事
about Barry.
我知道巴里
I know that Barry's...
你懂的  几乎算是你的弟弟
you know, practically your brother.
所以我也理解你显然会护着他
So I understand that your loyalty
而不会向着我
is obviously to him, not me.
我只是希望
But I was just hoping
或许你认为我配得上他
that maybe you think I'm good for him,
这样你就愿意帮我进一步了解他
so you'd want to help me figure him out.
我想说  假如你成功了解了他
Well, I mean, if you did that, you--
那你可就是史上第一人了
you would be the first.
太好了  瞬间希望满满啊
Wonderful. That gives me tons of hope.
只是
It's just, um...
他虽没有拒人于千里之外  可他
he's being not distant, but...
有所戒备
Guarded.
没错  他有所戒备
Yeah. He's being guarded.
他一直被噩梦惊醒
And he's waking up from these bad dreams
却不告诉我梦到了什么
and not telling me about them.
我也知道我们的关系发展得很快
And I know that we got close really quick.
只是感觉有什么东西把他拖住了
It's just...it's like there's something holding him back.
巴里是个这样的人
Here's the thing about Barry.
他有个坏习惯
He has a bad habit of
喜欢把所有压力都放在自己身上
carrying the weight of the world on his shoulders,
即便有些压力不需要他来承担
burdens that aren't even his to bear.
但他跟我不需要这样
But he doesn't have to do that with me.
那你更该让他知道你的想法
Which is exactly what you should tell him.
你别这样
No! Absolutely not!
你自己生气的时候可不能摔别人的东西
You don't get to throw somebody else's stuff when you're pissed off.
差不多得了
Thank you.
这是什么
What is this?
错误的答案
Wrong answers.
也许你问错了问题
Maybe you're asking the wrong questions.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
我最近一直在想这事儿
I've been thinking about this a lot recently.
我们一直都在想办法让巴里跑的更快
We keep trying to come up with ways to make Barry faster,
但我还是觉得我们能找到
but I still think we can figure out a way
让极速慢下来的办法
to make Zoom slower.
你忘了吗  我们已经试过了
We tried that already, remember?
那些镖根本没让他速度慢下来
Those darts didn't slow him down at all.
好吧  但我要说的不是那些镖
Yeah, I know--I'm not talking about the darts, okay?
镖显然没用  只是把他惹毛了
The darts clearly didn't work. They just pissed him off.
我要说的是另一件事
I'm talking about something else--
一个可以偷走极速速度的办法
a way we can steal Zoom's speed.
怎么偷
How?
乌龟人
The Turtle.
大家都知道
As some of you may well know,
我深陷一个秘密之中
I've been deeply embroiled in a secret,
跟一个看不见的敌人进行着单方面的斗争
one-sided battle with an invisible enemy.
别再提乌龟人了
No, not The Turtle again.
什么  什么是  或者说谁是乌龟人
What? What is the--or who is The Turtle?
西斯科的白鲸
It's Cisco's white whale.
一半是鲸鱼  一半是乌龟
Half whale, half turtle.
不是
No.
看你干的好事  凯特琳
Do you see what you're doing, Caitlin?
把大家都弄糊涂了
Everybody's confused now.
快说吧
Get to it.
当我们寻找逆闪时
I stumbled upon a few of these cases
我偶然发现了这几个案子
when we were looking for the Reverse Flash,
看起来像是以高速进行的抢劫
robberies that were seemingly committed at high speed...
人们上一秒还拿着心爱的东西
people holding their beloved items one second.
下一秒就消失不见了
Those items were gone the next.
告诉我你们看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
他的能力是什么  让时间停止
So he can...what? Stop time?
不  不  不  你看计时器
No, no, no. Look at the time code.
依然在走
It's still running.
好吧  假如他没让时间停止
Yeah, okay. So if he's not stopping time,
他在干什么
what is he doing?
他在让周围的事物都慢下来
He's slowing down everything around him.
这就是我们把他称为乌龟人的原因
And that is why we call him The Turtle.
为什么你从来没跟我提过这个人
Why have you never mentioned this guy to me before?
我也不知道
Oh, I don't know,
最近这段时间我们要应付的事有点多
I think we've just been a little distracted, you know,
寒冷队长
what with Captain Cold
天气巫师  还有大猩猩古鲁德
and the Weather Wizard and gorilla Grodd.
还要我往下说吗
Do I need to go on?
好吧  假如我们能抓到他
Okay, so if we can catch him,
弄清楚他是如何使用这种能力的
figure out how he uses his powers--
也许我们就能让极速体验到
Maybe we can show Zoom
慢节奏的生活是什么样的
what life is like in the slow lane.
我们要怎么才能找到他
How would you even know where to find him?
视频中的抢劫
Well, the robberies in the videos
都与被警局定性为物品遗失或丢失的报告一致
all correspond with police reports that were dismissed as lost or missing items
而不是盗窃
instead of thefts.
嫌犯的惯常目标是...
The suspect's M.O. being...
对某人有巨大价值的东西
Items of immense personal value.
新闻通稿  中城找回被盗钻石
看来中城警局要举行一场发布会
Oh, it appears that there's a press conference at CCPD,
因为范德沃特钻石已被找回
because the Vandervoort diamonds have just been recovered.
"我从地狱之心刺向你"[《白鲸记》]
"From hell's heart, I stab at thee."
这起无良罪案的犯案者
The perpetrators who committed this heartless crime
已经被逮捕并被羁押
have been apprehended and are now in our custody.
我们很高兴地宣布
And we're happy to report
著名的范德沃特钻石
that the famed Vandervoort diamonds
已经被归还至其合法所有人手中
have been returned to their rightful owner.
最可贵的是我曾祖父的戒指失而复得
The real gem is the return of my great-grandfather's ring.
戒指能重新回到我们家族
Getting that returned to the family
对我来说才是最重要的
is what's most priceless to me.
找到你了
Gotcha.
戒指不见了  它去哪儿了
The ring is gone. What happened to it?
封锁这个区域  谁也别离开这个房间
Lock this place down. No one leaves this room.
进行地毯式搜索
Sweep the precinct!
好消息是  不管乌龟人做了什么
Well, the good new is whatever The Turtle did,
对你的影响只是暂时的
it only affected you temporarily.
在龟速时间里是种什么感觉
What was it like being in Turtle time?
感觉很诡异
Yeah, no, it was weird.
就像是一股惰性波浪
It was like waves of inertness--
所有的能量突然都被吸走了
like all the energy was suddenly sucked out of my body,
过一会又回来了
and then it would return.
你的感受正是当时的状况
That's because that's exactly what was happening.
他有种能力
he has the ability to transfer
可以将身边的一切动能转移给自己
all the surrounding kinetic energy into himself.
让其他人短暂地处于势能当中
Leaving everyone else in a temporary state of potential energy.
没错
That's right.
那为什么我还能动
So why could I still move?
你的速度
Your speed.
你的速度能让你比别人
Your speed allows you to change positions
更快的变换位置
faster than anyone else.
这样你就可以把储存的势能
So you can convert your stored potential energy
转换回动能
back to kinetic energy.
等等  你要去哪儿
Excuse me, where are you going?
去试试看能否找出以此对抗极速的办法
Trying to figure out how to use this against Zoom.
别忘了还要对付极速
You remember Zoom?
"西斯科  跟我一起来吧
"Cisco, please join me.
我们将运用你的想法并把它带到新的科学高度
We'll use your idea and take it to new scientific heights
拯救这个世界"
and save the world."
好的  我很荣幸
Yes, I'd love to!
很好
Okay.
面部识别软件在新闻发布会录像中
Facial recognition software found us a match
找到了匹配的人
from the press conference footage.
乌龟人的名字叫罗素·格鲁森
The Turtle's name is Russell Glosson.
中城警局逮捕人员档案  罗素
他曾经是个三流小偷
He was a small-time thief
但在粒子加速器爆炸后就没再偷过东西了
who stopped thieving after the particle accelerator explosion.
好吧  我要去工作了
All right, I'm gonna head to work
跟乔汇报一下
Catch Joe up.
有什么其他发现再告诉我
Let me know if you find anything else.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  就只是...
Yeah, yeah, it's just, um...
很难看着这些东西
It's hard to...look at that
而不去想起我现在无法帮助任何人了
and not think about how I can't help people anymore.
我们这里有不少的科技
Well, we have lots of technology here.
不如让我们看看怎么帮你把速度拿回来
Why don't we figure out how to get your speed back?
我也是科学家  凯特琳
I'm a scientist too, Caitlin.
当我刚过来的时候
When I first got here,
我只专注于找回我的速度
all I did was work on how to get my speed back.
相信我  不管你想做什么测试
Believe me, whatever test you could run...
我都已经做过了
I've already done it.
乌龟人
The Turtle.
西斯科一直在找这家伙
Cisco's been looking for this guy forever.
辛格刚发布了对他的全面通缉令
Singh just put an APB out on him.
为什么其他人都比我先知道格鲁森的事
How did everybody know about Glosson before I did?
西斯科列了一整张表的身份不明超能力者
Cisco's got a whole list of unidentified metas.
这里的人都叫他
The boys around here are calling him
西斯科·德·拉曼恰
Cisco de la mancha.
改自：堂吉诃德·德·拉曼恰
《堂吉诃德》的作者
你没事吧  你看起来有点坐立不安的
Are you good? You seem a little jittery.
有点焦虑
A little anxious.
说实话吧
Let's be honest.
今晚和沃利聚餐这件事让我很紧张
I'm really nervous about this whole dinner tonight with Wally.
怎么了  你紧张个什么劲
Come on, why-why are you nervous?
你是世界上最好的爸爸
You're, like, the best dad ever.
他会发现的
He'll see that.
你能到场的话就简单多了
It'll be a whole lot easier, you being there.
乔  我会去的
Joe, I wouldn't miss it.
-今晚见  -好的
- See you tonight. - All right.
你好呀
Hey, you.
有时间吗
You got a sec?
有的
Yeah.
我就是...
I just, um...
我就是想确认下一切都好
I just want to make sure everything's okay.
好啊
Yeah.
我那个...
Yeah, I'm--I'm-I, uh...
不想太唠叨
Don't want to nag.
我不是那种人  我只是
That's not, you know, who I am. I just, uh...
我不想让你感觉到有负担什么的
I don't--I don't want you to feel burdened by anything.
没  我没有
No, I don't.
那好
Okay.
等下  帕蒂
Hey, wait. Patty, uh...
新年对我来说一直很难过
The new years was always a hard time for me.
因为我妈妈就是那时去世的
That's when my mom died,
所以只是那些记忆又都出来了
so it's just those memories all come out,
让人很难放下
and they're hard to put away.
所以如果你觉得我没和你交流
So if it feels like I haven't been communicating--
对不起  巴里  真对不起
I'm sorry, Barry. I'm sorry.
我不知道
I-I didn't know.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
你看  我们有段时间没过浪漫夜了
Look, um, we haven't had a romantic night in a while.
不如明天晚上
What do you say tomorrow night
咱们弄点吃的喝的
we get some dinner and drinks
然后也许来点接吻
and maybe a little...kissing?
听起来正是我们需要的
That sounds like what we need.
好的  那等会见
Okay. All right, I'll see you later.
好
Okay.
好了  我想咱们可以收摊了
Okay, I think we can call it.
沃利不会来了
Wally is not coming.
真抱歉  乔
I'm sorry, Joe.
我知道这对你来说有多重要
I know how much this meant to you.
他是个孩子  我懂的
He's a kid, right? I get it.
他最起码可以打个电话吧
He could have at least called.
可能有很多原因导致他没打
Well, there could be a number of reasons why he didn't.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for being here.
我爱你
I love you.
爱你
Love you.
明早见  小巴
See you in the morning, Bar.
好
Yeah.
韦斯特家族2.0版的开局可不太妙
Well, West family 2.0 is not really off to a great start.
你今晚也挺安静的
You've been quiet all evening.
乌龟人吗
The Turtle?
你怎么知道他的
How do you know about him?
不是...
No, um...
我只是脑子里事太多
No, I've just had a lot on my mind.
帕蒂
Patty?
我们...我们可能是一起喝了杯咖啡
We...we may have met for coffee.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
她真的很在乎你  巴里
She really cares about you, Barry,
她只是好奇你为什么那么戒备
And she's just wondering why you've been so guarded.
那你怎么跟她说的
And what did you tell her?
我让她和你谈谈
I told her to talk to you.
这可不好
Oh, that's not cool.
你知道  她倒是提到说
You know, she did mention that...
你最近在做噩梦
you've been having nightmares.
关于极速的
About Zoom...
杀死她的梦
killing her.
听着
Look.
我知道你俩之间的关系进展得很快
I know that things have been moving pretty fast between you two.
但你知道自己不可能一直瞒着她的  对吧
But you realize you can't keep things from her forever, right?
总有一天  你要告诉她真相
One day, you're gonna have to tell her the truth.
告诉她我是闪电侠吗
That I'm the flash?
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
巴里  我希望一年前你就告诉了我真相
Barry, I wish a year ago you had told me the truth.
所以怎么着  你觉得我应该告诉她吗
So, what, you think that I should just tell her?
我想如果你和她在一起是认真的
I think that if you are serious about being with her,
你就得告诉她
You have to.
那好  那我就这么做
All right, then that's what I'm gonna do.
我会告诉帕蒂我是闪电侠的
I'll tell Patty I'm the flash.
你们有什么发现吗
You guys got anything?
我想我们找到了这个三十多岁的
I think we found the next target
非忍者神龟超能力者的
for our 30-something, meta-human,
下一个目标
not-a-ninja-turtle.
你用了多久想出这个绰号的
How long did it take you to come up with that one?
我是脱口而出的  你没看见吗
It just came out of my mouth--did you see that?
-挺棒的  -挺好的
- That was amazing. - That was nice.
中城博物馆今晚将举办一场特殊的黑领结晚宴
Central City Museum is hosting a special black tie event tonight,
来展出"水晶球"
showcasing "The crystal ball."
是幅最近由马尔科夫
It's a famous painting, apparently,
修复好的名画
recently recovered from Markovia.
这幅画是西尔弗伯格家族
The painting is on loan to the museum
出借给博物馆的
from the Silverberg family.
水晶球
约翰·威廉水晶宫会展中心
中城博物馆
雅各伯·西尔弗伯格亲口说过
Jacob Silverberg himself said,
"这幅画的安全归还对我们而言
"The painting's safe return means more to us
比全世界的财富更意义重大"
than all the money in the world."
感觉他们在乞求乌龟人来抢夺这幅画
It's like they're begging Turtle to rob it.
没错  我有一个计划
Okay, yes. This is a plan.
这个乌龟人必将伺机而动
So The Turtle will make his move,
到时候我们就埋伏在那等着一举拿下他
and we can be there waiting to take him down.
你穿晚礼服是什么样子
How do you look in a tux?
来吧  他身高2米  方下巴
Come on, he's 6'2", he's square-jawed,
肌肉发达
and he's jacked.
一定很好看
I think he looks fine.
我身高2.1米
I'm 6'4".
糟糕
Oh, crap!
-怎么了  -没事
- Problem? - No.
没事
No.
这也许是个机会  等等
An opportunity, maybe. Hold on.
嘿  很高兴今晚能见到你
Hey, you. I'm excited to see you tonight.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
关于这个  我知道我跟你说过
Actually, about that-- um, so I know I said
"一起吃晚饭吧"  但是
"Let's have dinner," but, uh,
你一直想知道更多关于我的事
you've been wanting me to share more.
所以我想告诉你
So I thought that I would share that
我热爱艺术
I love art.
挺有趣的
Okay, interesting.
我对艺术非常热衷
No, I just, you know, I can't get enough of art.
总之  今晚在中城博物馆有一场会展
Anyway, there's this event at the Central City Museum tonight.
将会展出一幅
They're showing this really famous painting
我一直都很喜爱的名画
that I've always loved.
其实  我对艺术一窍不通
Actually, I don't know anything about art,
但是那句话怎么说来着
but what's the saying?
我知道我喜欢什么
I know what I like,
我喜欢你
and I like you,
我会陪你去
so count me in.
很好  我们八点见
All right, great. I'll see you at 8:00.
-是七点  -还是七点见吧
- 7:00! - Or 7:00.
我们七点见
I'll see you at 7:00.
好的  就七点了
Okay, 7:00 it is.
再见
Bye.
你是个非常棒的超级英雄
You know, you're a really great superhero--
-谢谢  -一个非常棒的超级英雄
- Thanks. - A really great superhero--
-谢谢你  -但是你觉得
- Thank you. - But do you think
在打击罪犯的时候约会
it's a good idea when you're fighting crime
合适吗
to bring a date?
我打算告诉帕蒂我就是闪电侠
I'm gonna tell Patty that I'm the Flash.
这是个馊主意吗  大家怎么看
Is that a bad idea? What do we think?
她可是让鲨鱼王和哈里吃过枪子的
I will say, she put bullets in King Shark and Harry.
-没错  -所以依我所见
- Yeah. - So as far as I'm concerned,
挺适合加入闪电侠小组
that's Team Flash material to me.
没错  谢谢你  西斯科
All right, yes. Thank you, Cisco.
谢谢  太酷了
Yeah, thank you. Cool.
我准备这么做了
I'm gonna do this--
我要告诉她
I'm gonna tell her.
不要告诉她
Don't tell her.
你真心在乎这个女人
You care for this woman.
这很好
That's nice.
那就让她尽可能远离真相
Then keep her as far away from this as possible.
我告诉你为什么
And here's why.
如果极速发现了你所在乎之人
If Zoom finds out who you care for,
你所至爱之人
who you love,
你所依存之人
who you live for,
他就会从你身边夺走他们
he'll take them from you.
水晶球  约翰·威廉水晶宫会展中心
好了
All right.
时刻注意着乌龟人
Keep your eyes open for The Turtle.
没想到我也会说出这句话
A sentence I never thought I would say.
西斯科  你和哈里就位了吗
Cisco, are you and Harry in position?
我在监控现场
I'm the security feed.
我已经打开了面部识别设备
I've got the facial recognition software running,
以便我们能在乌龟人行动之前发现他
so we'll be able to spot Turtle before he makes his move.
乌龟人
Turtle.
你为什么要执着于给他们起这种荒谬的绰号
Why do you insist on giving them ridiculous nicknames?
说我吗
Me?
想出"极速"这个绰号的天才是谁
Who's the genius that came up with "Zoom"?
好吧
Yeah, well...
我要告诉你一件事  大约两年前
I'll tell you, about two years ago...
发生在地球二
This is on Earth-2, now.
那里的中城警察
The CCPD there--
接到报警电话
they got a 911 call
报告了一起绑架人质事件
about a hostage situation,
但当特警队抵达现场时
but when the SWAT team got there,
那里根本没有人质
there were no hostages.
这是一个陷阱
It was a trap.
极速设下的陷进
Zoom set a trap
为了向警方展示他们无法抓住他
in order to show the police that they could not stop him.
而且他还杀害了十四名警察
And he killed 14 officers.
男女都有  简直是一场屠杀
Men and women. Slaughtered them.
只留下了一个活口讲述事情的经过
Left one alive to tell what happened.
那个警察的描述是
That officer described
有一道蓝光
blue lightning
极速闪过
"Zooming" all about.
瞬间他的战友们
As his comrades,
他全副武装的兄弟姐妹们
brothers and sisters in arms,
全部被杀死了
were murdered.
那名警察
That officer...
认为自己是个幸运儿
considered himself to be a lucky one,
能够逃过这一劫来讲述这场灾难
spared in order to tell the tale.
直到极速去他家杀害他的那晚
Until Zoom went to his house that night and killed him too.
总之  这就是"极速"这绰号的由来
Anyway, that's how he got the nickname "Zoom".
如果你需要我用震波
If you ever need me to vibe...
让你知道你女儿是否还活着
so you can know if she's still alive--
她还活着
She's alive.
好的
Right.
-不  -不
- No! - No!
你的表情非常怪异
You have a really weird look on your face.
-我看着很怪吗  -没  没有
- Do I look weird? - No, no.
你看上去很梦幻
You...Look...Like a dream.
你也非常帅
You look very handsome.
我迫不及待想看看那幅画了
I can't wait to see this painting.
什么画
What painting?
那幅画
The painting. Uh, yeah.
我也很期待
Me too, um, yeah.
我们还是先聊聊吧
How about we talk first?
我就等你说这句话呢
I thought you'd never ask.
我看不透你  巴里·艾伦
I can't figure you out, Barry Allen.
因为我在极力
That is because I work hard
隐藏真实的自己
to hide who I really am.
你不必对我隐藏
You don't have to hide with me.
我只是必须
I just have to
十分信任某人
really trust someone
才能把真相告诉他们
if they're gonna know the truth.
是吗
Do you?
我信任你  帕蒂
I trust you, Patty.
我也信任你
I trust you, too.
帕蒂...
Patty, um...
那次我被闪电击中后
After I was struck by lightning,
等我醒来时...
when I woke up...
我们发现乌龟人了
We've got eyes on Turtle.
巴里  你刚说什么
Barry, you were saying?
我得走了  很抱歉
I have to go. I'm sorry.
什么  什么
What? What?
可是  巴里...
But Barry...
中城警局  不许动
CCPD! Freeze!
怎么回事
What?
你是和闪电侠一样快吗
Are you as fast as the Flash?
才没有  他要慢得多
Oh, no. He is much slower.
这是陷阱吗
This is a trap?
我是慢
I'm slow--
但不傻
Not stupid.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
我扶着  走吧
I got it. Come on.
你瞳孔正常
Your pupils are normal.
心率稍慢
Your heart rate's a little low.
但除此之外  没有脑震荡的症状
But other than that, no concussive symptoms.
我真的没事  乌龟人抓到了吗
I really do feel fine. What about turtle?
-他失踪了  -那幅画也是
- No sign of him. - Or the painting.
他一定是在混乱中把画带走了
He, uh, must have gotten away with it in the chaos.
没错  事情有点不顺
Yeah, things went a little sideways
因为你女朋友突然
after your girlfriend decided
想和乌龟人上演《致命武器》全集
to go all "Lethal weapon" 1 through 4 on Turtle.
天啊
Oh, my god.
帕蒂会以为我丢下了她
Patty's gonna think I ditched her.
不行  我得走了
I--no, I got to go.
你去哪...
Where are you--
现在要紧的是找到乌龟人
Finding Turtle is what's important right now.
是  但去找她对我来说也很要紧
Yeah, uh, this is important to me too.
我们还没给你检查速度是否恢复了
But we need to see if your speed still works.
看起来是恢复了
I think-- I think it still works.
我们仍需搞清乌龟人是如何吸收速度的
We still have to find out how Turtle drained him of it.
能和你聊聊吗
Can I talk to you...
就一会儿
for a second?
你还没来得及喝香槟
You never got your champagne.
可惜找不到乐队演奏了
I couldn't find any flutes.
希望这样没问题
Hope that's okay.
当然了
Of course.
给你
Here you go.
我来看看自己能不能派上用场
Let me go see if I can make myself useful.
中途岛大学
鉴证科学系
帕蒂·斯皮沃特
我猜对了
I was right.
我以为你会一脸不快  结果真是
I thought that you would look mad, and you do.
怎么回事
What happened?
我真的没有一个好理由
I don't really have a good excuse.
没理由
Nothing?
没理由  拜托  巴里
Nothing? I mean, come on, Barry.
任何理由都比没理由强
Anything is better than nothing.
我是说  拜托
I mean, come on.
老天啊  我一直在做一个称职的女友
Holy crap, I've been a really, really cool girlfriend.
大多数女孩没有自尊心
Most girls don't have the self-esteem
承受这么多计划
to handle the--plans?
没计划  那也好
no plans. That's cool.
还有...
Or the--or the...
再次半夜从梦中惊醒尖叫
Waking up in the middle of the night screaming again.
好的  也无所谓
Fine, whatever.
之后又是很美好的计划
And then--and then the really, really fancy plans...
那是很棒
Which were awesome.
结果在我性命攸关时把我丢下
And then you ditched me right before I almost died.
你要是这么说的话  那...
I mean, when you put it that way, it--
我真的很难过
I'm actually really upset.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们一起快乐过
Look, we've been having fun.
非常快乐
And fun has been so great.
但我要把这些快乐
But...I'm moving past fun
做一个了结
to the close part.
这是我想要的  好吗
That's what I want, okay?
我决定要这样
That's where I'm going.
你需要弄清楚你想要什么
You need to figure out what it is that you want.
越快越好
And do it fast.
快是我的专长
Fast is my specialty.
交出来吧
Yo, pay up.
怎么
What?
你派人跟踪我了吗
You got someone tailing me now?
你昨晚为什么没来吃晚餐
Why didn't you show up for dinner last night?
我没赶上
Couldn't make it.
如果和别人约好了要去
You tell someone you're gonna be somewhere,
你必须去
You show up.
大概是没有爸爸教过我这些道理吧
Guess I didn't have my dad to teach me that, huh?
这就是你来中城的原因吗
Is this why you came to Central City?
不来熟悉我和你姐姐
Not to get to know me or your sister,
却参加这种东西
But this nonsense?
楔石城已经没人敢和我赛了
No one in Keystone will race me anymore.
但我真心没必要对你解释什么
But I don't actually have to explain myself to you.
实际上  有必要
Actually, you do.
这是违法的  我是警察  没忘吧
This is illegal. I'm a cop, remember?
对  没错
Oh, yeah. Yes.
一个不知道自己还有个儿子的警探
The detective who didn't know he had a son
而且对我一无所知
and who doesn't know anything about me.
我在努力去了解你  沃利
I am trying to get to know you, Wally.
这些赛事  那车
These races-- that car--
是我赢来的
that I won?
我只有这样才能付得起我妈的医疗费
That's the only way that I can pay for my mom's hospital bills,
这样才能让她得到治疗
get her the help that she needs.
你不用这样做的
You don't have to do this.
我存了点钱  我可以先拿出一点养老金
I have money saved. I can dip into my pension.
我不需要你的钱
I don't need your money.
我能照顾好我和我妈  懂吗
I can take care of myself and my mom, okay?
我才是家里的顶梁柱
I'm the man of our house.
已经容不下别人了
That position has been filled.
回你那个家去吧  乔
Go home to your family, Joe.
巴里
Barry?
怎么回事
What?
你想要什么
What do you want from me?
我想要闪电侠最宝贵的东西
The thing most precious to the Flash--
你
You.
帕蒂
Patty?
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
糟了
No.
快点
Come on.
不  乔
No—Joe!
乔  我觉得乌龟人带走了帕蒂
Joe, um, I think the Turtle has patty.
我...
I--
赶快到尖端科研实验室见我  好吗
look, just meet me at S.T.A.R. Labs, all right?
燧发手枪文物丢失  中城日报
你想对我怎样
What do you want from me?
我想让你别动
I want you to stop moving...
永远别动
Forever.
杀了我你能得到什么
What do you get out of killing me?
我没打算杀你
Oh, I'm not gonna kill you.
杀了你太快太麻烦了
That's much too--- fast and messy.
我做事喜欢优雅缓慢
I like to take things nice and slow.
你不用为了证明什么来伤害我
You don't have to hurt me to try to prove a point.
我这不是为了伤害你
This isn't about hurting you.
我是为了伤害珍惜你的人
This is about hurting someone who values you.
谁  巴里吗
Who, Barry?
不
No.
是闪电侠
The Flash.
他跟我有什么关系
What does he have to do with this?
我看到他奋不顾身的去救你
I saw the way he saved you.
没错  他就是那种人
Yes, that's what he does.
他是个英雄
He's a hero.
谁有需要他就去救谁
He saves people who need saving.
真是浪费时间
That's a waste of time...
拯救大众
Saving people.
他们把所有东西都视作理所当然
They take everything for granted.
所以你就夺走对他们最重要的东西
So you take the things that matter most to them.
我的妻子罗莎琳把我视作理所应当
My wife Rosalyn took me for granted.
她想要离开我
She wanted to leave me--
她是对我来说最重要的人
the thing I valued most.
所以就是因为这个吗
So that's what this is about?
因为妻子离开了你所以你很受伤
You're hurt because your wife left you?
我不能让她离开我
I couldn't let that happen.
所以我把她变成了我的
So I made her mine.
永远是我的
Forever.
帕蒂·斯皮沃特警探
我希望我没把你的名字拼错
I do hope I spelled your name right.
小巴  我们会找到她的
Bar-- we'll find her.
我找不到这个人的任何线索
I'm not getting any leads on this guy.
就好像是他彻底消失了一样
It's like he's totally fallen off the grid.
你知道吗  所有他偷的东西
You know, it-- any of the stuff he's stolen,
-我都找不到  -他都自己留着
- I can't find it. - He keeps them.
就像是连环杀人犯收集战利品一样
He keeps them the way a serial killer collects trophies.
他偷了好多东西
He's stolen a lot of stuff.
所以他需要一个很大的地方来存着  对不对
Which means he needs a lot of space to store it, right?
我们就从这里入手
That's where we start.
查查他有没有租用什么仓库
See if he rented any storage spaces.
罗素·格鲁森
不不
No, no...
我什么也没找到
I'm not getting anything.
等等
Wait a minute.
在内道尔图书馆没关的时候
His ex-wife used to be an archivist for antiquities
他的前妻是那里的文物保管员
at the Naydel Library before it shut down,
罗莎莉·格鲁森  内道尔图书馆
粒子加速器爆炸后三个月图书馆关闭了
And it shut down three months after the accelerator exploded.
那里足够存放乌龟人的东西
That place is big enough to hold Turtle's stuff.
好的  我知道了
Okay, all right.
等等  巴里  我们还没想出来
Wait, Barry-- we haven't even figured out
怎么消除乌龟人的超能力呢
how to neutralize the Turtle's power.
那我就用我的超能力硬闯
Well, I'm gonna have to power through it.
好了  我到图书馆外了
All right, I'm outside the library.
巴里  要救出帕蒂的唯一方法就是
Barry, the only way to save Patty
你在乌龟人两次脉冲之间把她带出来
is if you grab her in between each of the turtle's pulses.
你只有0.2秒的时间
You'll only have 2/10ths of a second
来行动
to make your moves.
没问题
I got it.
不要
No!
我估计他没我想的
I guess he doesn't care about you
那么在乎你
as much as I thought.
不要
No...
别  别  求你了
No, no...Please!
没事了
No, it's all right.
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
无论你是谁  都谢谢你
Thank you, whoever you are.
没事了
It's okay.
你好  乌龟人
Hey, Turtle.
你想知道现在最讽刺的是什么吗
So you want to know my new definition of irony?
现在你变成我们的战利品了
Now you... are our most prized possession.
-帕蒂还好吗  -她还好
- Patty okay? - She is, yeah.
杰伊
Jay?
怎么了
Yeah?
我知道了
I know.
你为什么不告诉我你病了
Why didn't you tell me that you're sick?
那杯香槟
The champagne.
你从杯子上提取了我的DNA
You took my DNA off the glass.
你知道我失去了我的丈夫后
You know I lost my husband--
走出那段阴影有多么困难
how hard that was for me to move on.
你明知道我很快也会失去你
How could you let me get close to you
却放任我走近你
knowing that soon I'd lose you too?
我只是
I just...
这在我预料
I didn't expect...
之外
this.
你在我预料之外
I didn't expect you.
那就帮我找到解药
Then help me find a cure.
没有解药
There is no cure.
唯一能救我的办法就是找回我的速度
The only way to save me is to get my speed back.
而唯一的办法就是阻止极速
And the only way to do that is to stop Zoom.
那就阻止他
Then let's stop him.
好
Yeah.
我想我前几天把毛衣留在这里了
I think I left my sweater here the other night.
绿色的
It's green.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我就觉得那不像是巴里的
I thought that didn't look like Barry's.
我今晚要回楔石城了
Heading back to Keystone tonight.
短暂地旅行
That's a fast trip.
中城对我来说越来越危险了
Yeah, well, it's getting a little hot in Central City for me.
别担心
Don't worry.
回去的路上  我尽量少闯红灯
I'll try not to run too many lights on the way there.
如果你在等着我道歉的话
You know, if you're waiting for an apology,
你是等不到的
it's not coming.
不
No.
不  我才应该向你道歉
No, I'm... I'm the one that should be apologizing to you.
你成长的时候
I felt bad
我不在你身边陪伴  我感觉很难过
not being there while you were growing up, and...
而父子团聚这事我太过心急了
I was pushing this whole father-son thing.
对不起
I'm sorry.
咱们慢慢来吧
Let's just slow down a bit.
我不会再想立刻成为你爸爸
I won't try to be your instant dad,
你也不必假装你想成为我儿子
and you won't have to pretend that you want to be my son.
怎么样
Deal?
这些东西你一个人吃吗
All that food for you?
也不一定
Doesn't have to be.
喜欢炒面吗
You like chow mein?
不喜欢
No.
但我喜欢宫保鸡丁
But I like Kung Pao Chicken.
首字母大写  签名
Initial and sign.
好了  谢谢你们
There you go. Thank you, guys.
帕蒂
Patty.
你好
Hi.
能谈谈吗  好好谈谈
can we talk-- like, really talk?
好  不行
Yeah, uh, no.
现在真的不是时候
Now's not really an awesome time.
我桌上有堆积如山的文件要完成
I have a mound of paperwork on my desk I need to finish,
抱歉  我没时间谈
so I'm sorry, I can't.
没事  我就说两句话
No, no, okay. Real-- really quick.
你说得对
So you were right.
你对所有事的看法都是正确的
You were right about everything.
我最近是有点疏远  表现奇怪
I've been closed off and weird,
包括你指责我的一切
and, um, all the things that you said I was.
但大部分原因是我没坦诚相告
But mostly, I have not been honest.
巴里
Barry,
我要离开中城
I'm leaving Central City.
什么
What?
在马登  我爸爸  一切事情发生之前
Before Mardon, and before my dad-- before everything--
我一直想参加犯罪现场调查
I always wanted to be a CSI.
四年前  我被中途岛城市大学的
And four years ago, I was accepted
法医科学项目录取了
into the forensic science program at Midway City University.
那真的是一所好学校
That's a really great school.
嗯
Yeah.
我知道  我只是
Yeah, I know, I just, uh...
我没去上
I didn't go.
我决定成为一名警察
You know, I deferred to become a cop and...
抓住杀死我爸爸的凶手
catch my dad's killer.
我已经做到了
And I've done that.
所以
So, um...
是时候向前看了
so it's time to move on.
工作方面吗
From the job?
所有方面
From everything.
帕蒂  帕蒂
Patty. Patty--
帕
Pat--
日志记录编号113
Journal log entry number 113.
杰西
Jess...
我很快就回去救你
I'm coming for you soon.
我保证
I promise.
今天早些时候我在想
I was thinking earlier today about the time
在你四岁的时候
that you were four.
我带你去天文馆  就你和我两人
I took you to the planetarium, just you and me.
我记得  因为那是我第一次
I remember because it was the first time
单独一人带你外出
I took you out all by myself.
当时天文馆里很多人
The planetarium was crowded,
你拚命拉着我的手
and you held my hand for dear life,
也可能是我拚命地拉着你的手
or maybe it was the other way around.
但是在火星展览那  我把你弄丢了
But it was in the mars exhibit that I lost you.
我惊慌失措
Panic.
一分钟我就把那地方给封锁了
I had that place locked down in one minute.
让每一个保安去找你
I had every security guard looking for you.
我感觉到恐惧涌向全身
And I could feel the fear rise in the back of my throat
同时还有别的感觉涌出  某种...
and something else rising also, some...
我体内的黑暗天性
dark instinct inside me
让我想着要如何对付
about what I would do
那个抓走你的人
to the person who had taken you--
我会做出的事
the things I would do...
难以言表的事
unspeakable things.
就在那一刻我意识到了
And it was in that moment that I realized,
百分之百地肯定
for certain,
我会不惜一切也要把你救回来
that I would do anything to get you back.
-吉迪恩  -在  斯旺教授
- Gideon. - Yes, Professor Thawne?
我在哪里
Where the hell am I?